export type Multiplication = {
  question: string;
  result: number;
  answer: number;
};

export const TABLE1: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '1 X 1 = ',
    result: 1,
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 2 = ',
    result: 2,
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 3 = ',
    result: 3,
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 4 = ',
    result: 4,
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 5 = ',
    result: 5,
    answer: 5,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 6 = ',
    result: 6,
    answer: 6,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 7 = ',
    result: 7,
    answer: 7,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 8 = ',
    result: 8,
    answer: 8,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 9 = ',
    result: 9,
    answer: 9,
  },
  {
    question: '1 X 10 = ',
    result: 10,
    answer: 10,
  },
];
export const TABLE2: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '2 X 1 = ',
    result: 2,
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 2 = ',
    result: 4,
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 3 = ',
    result: 6,
    answer: 6,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 4 = ',
    result: 8,
    answer: 8,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 5 = ',
    result: 10,
    answer: 10,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 6 = ',
    result: 12,
    answer: 12,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 7 = ',
    result: 14,
    answer: 14,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 8 = ',
    result: 16,
    answer: 16,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 9 = ',
    result: 18,
    answer: 18,
  },
  {
    question: '2 X 10 = ',
    result: 20,
    answer: 20,
  },
];
export const TABLE3: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '3 X 1 = ',
    result: 3,
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 2 = ',
    result: 6,
    answer: 6,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 3 = ',
    result: 9,
    answer: 9,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 4 = ',
    result: 12,
    answer: 12,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 5 = ',
    result: 15,
    answer: 15,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 6 = ',
    result: 18,
    answer: 18,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 7 = ',
    result: 21,
    answer: 21,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 8 = ',
    result: 24,
    answer: 24,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 9 = ',
    result: 27,
    answer: 27,
  },
  {
    question: '3 X 10 = ',
    result: 30,
    answer: 30,
  },
];
export const TABLE4: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '4 X 1 = ',
    result: 4,
    answer: 4,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 2 = ',
    result: 8,
    answer: 8,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 3 = ',
    result: 12,
    answer: 12,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 4 = ',
    result: 16,
    answer: 16,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 5 = ',
    result: 20,
    answer: 20,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 6 = ',
    result: 24,
    answer: 24,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 7 = ',
    result: 28,
    answer: 28,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 8 = ',
    result: 32,
    answer: 32,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 9 = ',
    result: 36,
    answer: 36,
  },
  {
    question: '4 X 10 = ',
    result: 40,
    answer: 40,
  },
];
export const TABLE5: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '5 X 1 = ',
    result: 5,
    answer: 5,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 2 = ',
    result: 10,
    answer: 10,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 3 = ',
    result: 15,
    answer: 15,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 4 = ',
    result: 20,
    answer: 20,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 5 = ',
    result: 25,
    answer: 25,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 6 = ',
    result: 30,
    answer: 30,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 7 = ',
    result: 35,
    answer: 35,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 8 = ',
    result: 40,
    answer: 40,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 9 = ',
    result: 45,
    answer: 45,
  },
  {
    question: '5 X 10 = ',
    result: 50,
    answer: 50,
  },
];
export const TABLE6: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '6 X 1 = ',
    result: 6,
    answer: 6,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 2 = ',
    result: 12,
    answer: 12,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 3 = ',
    result: 18,
    answer: 18,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 4 = ',
    result: 24,
    answer: 24,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 5 = ',
    result: 30,
    answer: 30,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 6 = ',
    result: 36,
    answer: 36,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 7 = ',
    result: 42,
    answer: 42,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 8 = ',
    result: 48,
    answer: 48,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 9 = ',
    result: 54,
    answer: 54,
  },
  {
    question: '6 X 10 = ',
    result: 60,
    answer: 60,
  },
];
export const TABLE7: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '7 X 1 = ',
    result: 7,
    answer: 7,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 2 = ',
    result: 14,
    answer: 14,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 3 = ',
    result: 21,
    answer: 21,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 4 = ',
    result: 28,
    answer: 28,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 5 = ',
    result: 35,
    answer: 35,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 6 = ',
    result: 42,
    answer: 42,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 7 = ',
    result: 49,
    answer: 49,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 8 = ',
    result: 56,
    answer: 56,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 9 = ',
    result: 63,
    answer: 63,
  },
  {
    question: '7 X 10 = ',
    result: 70,
    answer: 70,
  },
];
export const TABLE8: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '8 X 1 = ',
    result: 8,
    answer: 8,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 2 = ',
    result: 16,
    answer: 16,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 3 = ',
    result: 24,
    answer: 24,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 4 = ',
    result: 32,
    answer: 32,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 5 = ',
    result: 40,
    answer: 40,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 6 = ',
    result: 48,
    answer: 48,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 7 = ',
    result: 56,
    answer: 56,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 8 = ',
    result: 64,
    answer: 64,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 9 = ',
    result: 72,
    answer: 72,
  },
  {
    question: '8 X 10 = ',
    result: 80,
    answer: 80,
  },
];
export const TABLE9: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '9 X 1 = ',
    result: 9,
    answer: 9,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 2 = ',
    result: 18,
    answer: 18,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 3 = ',
    result: 27,
    answer: 27,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 4 = ',
    result: 36,
    answer: 36,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 5 = ',
    result: 45,
    answer: 45,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 6 = ',
    result: 54,
    answer: 54,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 7 = ',
    result: 63,
    answer: 63,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 8 = ',
    result: 72,
    answer: 72,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 9 = ',
    result: 81,
    answer: 81,
  },
  {
    question: '9 X 10 = ',
    result: 90,
    answer: 90,
  },
];
export const TABLE10: Multiplication[] = [
  {
    question: '10 X 1 = ',
    result: 10,
    answer: 10,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 2 = ',
    result: 20,
    answer: 20,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 3 = ',
    result: 30,
    answer: 30,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 4 = ',
    result: 40,
    answer: 40,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 5 = ',
    result: 50,
    answer: 50,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 6 = ',
    result: 60,
    answer: 60,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 7 = ',
    result: 70,
    answer: 70,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 8 = ',
    result: 80,
    answer: 80,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 9 = ',
    result: 90,
    answer: 90,
  },
  {
    question: '10 X 10 = ',
    result: 100,
    answer: 100,
  },
];

export const TABLES = [
  ...TABLE1,
  ...TABLE2,
  ...TABLE3,
  ...TABLE4,
  ...TABLE5,
  ...TABLE6,
  ...TABLE7,
  ...TABLE8,
  ...TABLE9,
  ...TABLE10,
];

function shuffle(array: Multiplication[]) {
  let currentIndex = array.length;
  let randomIndex;

  // While there remain elements to shuffle.
  while (currentIndex > 0) {
    // Pick a remaining element.
    randomIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * currentIndex);
    currentIndex--;

    // And swap it with the current element.
    [array[currentIndex], array[randomIndex]] = [
      array[randomIndex],
      array[currentIndex],
    ];
  }

  return array;
}
